Now that you have your local program environment all set up,
你已经设置好本地编程环境
it's time to try out different inputs.
现在该尝试不同的输入了
Programs can get a lot more interesting
当程序能够与外部信息交互时
when they can interact with external information.
会变得非常有趣
First, let's try getting raw input from the user.
首先 我们尝试获取用户的原始输入
Here's what I mean.
也就是说
This program prompts the user to enter a name,
这个程序会提示用户输入一个名字
and picks in that input as a string to use in its code.
然后将该输入当做字符串用在代码中
This input function is what takes in the user's input as a string.
这个函数 input 会接受用户的输入并转换为字符串
It has an optional argument that you can use to specify a prompt shown to the user.
它有一个可选参数 用于指定显示给用户的提示
Since the input function interprets input as a string,
因为函数 input 将输入解析为字符串
you'll need to wrap the result with int or float if you want to use it as a number.
所以如果你想将整数或浮点数当做数字 则需要用 int 或 float 封装该数字
If you don't do this and try to use the input as a number, you'll get an error.
如果不这么做并尝试将输入当做数字 你将遇到错误
Here, I wrap the input with int and added 20 to it.
在此示例中 我用 int 封装输入并使其加 20
But what if the user inputs a non integer number?
如果用户输入非整型数字呢？
You can just wrap it as a float to catch non integer numbers as well.
你可以将其封装为 float 以涵盖非整型数字
But what if you need an integer,
如果需要整型呢
like if you're multiplying a string by it to repeat it a certain number of times?
例如使字符串乘以一个整数以便重复一定次数
This wouldn't work with the float even if it's an integer number.
使用浮点型就不行 即使该数字是整型数字
We can actually wrap this int with float,
我们实际上可以用 float 封装这个 int
and then convert it into an int like this.
然后像这样将其转换为 int
Okay, that works.
可以了
Clearly, you're trying to imagine and handle
很明显 如果要考虑用户输入的每种情形
every possible case with user input can quickly get complicated.
代码很快就变得复杂起来
We addressed some cases here,
我们处理了某些情形
but there are also loads of other cases we didn't address that could lead to more errors.
但是还有很多其他情形没有考虑到 并且会导致更多错误
We'll learn a better way to handle these scenarios in the next section.
我们将在下个部分了解处理这些情形的更好方式
Before we move on to practice,
在转到练习部分之前
here's another way we can interpret user input.
再介绍解析用户输入的另一种方式
Eval is a built-in function that evaluates a string as a line of Python.
eval() 是一个内置函数 并将字符串评估为一行 Python
You can even include variables in the string like this.
甚至可以像这样在字符串中包含变量
Now, let's write some fun scripts that interact with user input.
现在我们将编写一些与用户输入交互的有趣脚本